meltdownchallenge.com 2016-04-09

# Privacy policy

Data security as well as privacy is very important to MeltDownChallenge.com. This document summarizes the measures we’ve undertaken to ensure that only the user data necessary to effectively run our programs is used, stored and captured. MeltDownChallenge.com collects data in a secure manner that goes beyond industry standards; and has plans and programs available to effectively detect and handle security breaches, should these occur. This Policy applies to the website www.MeltDownChallenge.com. By using our website users confirm to be informed about and comply with this privacy policy.

###  Information Collected by MeltDownChallenge.com

####  User Profile

To improve the fun of the challenge experience, MeltDownChallenge.com offers personalization options for User Profiles. These personalization options cover information such as birth date, weight, diet practices, smoking habits and other related topics. Photos can also be part of the User Profile.

####  Challenge Profile

To participate in MeltDownChallenge.com challenges, users can opt to supply information such as weight, target weight, age, gender, bet amount, cholesterol level, stress test results, workout regiments etc. MeltDownChallenge.com can also collect payment information such as credit or debit card numbers, expiration dates, bank account numbers, PayPal account information etc.

####  Friends

Users can opt to identify friends, family, colleagues or other third party members through the invite-a-friend functions. If users do this MeltDownChallenge.com collects the selected third party’s email address and will automatically send the recipients an email, and if necessary, reminder emails. MeltDownChallenge.com stores this information solely for the purpose of sending the aforementioned email and related reminder emails as well as to track the effect of the invite-a-friend function. Third parties can always contact MeltDownChallenge.com to request the removal of their information from our database.

####  Orders

If users purchase product or services through MeltDownChallenge.com, billing information (such as credit card numbers, expiration dates, PayPal information and/or bank account numbers) and address information (such as name, email address, and shipping address) will be collected.

####  Challenge Measurements

To participate in challenges, users must submit several kinds of specific information at the beginning and ending of a challenge. This includes weigh-in photos, cholesterol levels, stress test scores and smoking habit information. This information is used for the sole purpose to confirm a user's starting and ending scores/levels. MeltDownChallenge.com does not use this information for any other purpose without the written permission of the user. After review, the information is stored in our database and later used to determine challenge winners. The information is also displayed on the user’s personal profile and is visible to whomever the user has allowed it to be visible to in the personal settings.  
Upon occasion, Meltdown Challenge LLC does share site analytics including before and after pictures with team challenge hosts. This pertains to the "Six Weeks to Summer Meltdown to Health" Challenges starting May 5th, 2014.

####  Walls, Blogs, Chats & Forums

Users should be aware that the information shared on walls, blogs, chatrooms and/or forums on MeltDownChallenge.com can be read, collected and/ or used by other users of the aforesaid oultets, which can sometimes lead to information sharing with third parties, and consequent unsollicited messages. MeltDownChallenge.com is not responsible for information that users choose to submit in these outlets. This also applied for third-party services like Facebook, Twitter and Google + that MeltDownChallenge.com connects to.

###  Personal Information Usage

Information collected through Meltdownchallenge.com is used to run the services Meltdownchallenge.com offers, as described on the website and in this policy. Information will not be shared or disclosed unless it’s for the purposes described in this policy. To be able to run our programs and offer our services, we may use personal information for: (i) providing you with important information about Meltdownchallenge.com including but not limited to important updates and notifications; (ii) sending you emails and/or mobile alerts and/or reminders including invitations to other challenges; (iii) adjusting your Meltdownchallenge.com challenge page to increase effectiveness of your health challenge and progress; and (iv) determining relevant services to you, your geographic location and your lifestyle.  
Upon occasion, Meltdown Challenge LLC does share site analytics including before and after pictures with team challenge hosts. 

###  Personal Information Sharing

Meltdownchallenge.com does not view and/or disclose user’s personal information unless deemed necessary for the following purposes:

####  Providing Services & Functions

Meltdownchallenge.com works with a variety of third parties to carry out functions and services. Such functions include wireless services, website hosting, product shipping and delivery, services provided on Meltdownchallenge.com, sending e-mails and/or texts, data analysis, marketing and PR assistance, payment processing and customer service. These third parties may gain access to information to carry out their services for Meltdownchallenge.com.

####  Compliance with Laws & Legal Processes

Meltdownchallenge.com may release personal information when such action is deemed necessary to comply with the law and/or legal processes and protect the personal safety and security of Meltdownchallenge.com users and/or others.

####  Protecting Our Rights & Property

Meltdownchallenge.com may release personal information when such action is deemed necessary to protect and defend our rights and/or property. This includes the enforcement of agreements and policies and exchanging information with third parties for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

####  User Profile Information

Information collected during registration and profile customization, such as full name, gender and location, may be displayed to other users on Meltdownchallenge.com. The User Profile is where users share information about themselves. Users can control which information is displayed in the User Profiles. Meltdownchallenge.com allows third parties access to all information that users have chosen to made visible to the public through the Meltdownchallenge.com website. Meltdownchallenge.com keeps passwords and answers to security questions private.  
Upon occasion, Meltdown Challenge LLC does share site analytics including before and after pictures with team challenge hosts. This pertains to the "Six Weeks to Summer Meltdown to Health" Challenges starting May 5th, 2014.

####  Corporate Participation

If users participate through a company, then Meltdownchallenge.com may share user information with this company if so requested. We may also receive information, if necessary for our programs and services, all to the extent permitted by federal and state privacy laws and regulations.  
Upon occasion, Meltdown Challenge LLC does share site analytics including before and after pictures with team challenge hosts. This pertains to the "Six Weeks to Summer Meltdown to Health" Challenges starting May 5th, 2014.

Except for the aforementioned purposes, in all other cases Meltdownchallenge.com will not share users' personally identifiable information with third parties without their prior permission.

###  Controlling Information Visibility

Users may choose not to disclose information, but this may lead to the inability to use certain services and functions on Meltdownchallenge.com.

Users can correct, add and delete personally identifiable information on our website by visiting their profile. A copy of the unrevised information will often be maintained in our records as part of regularly scheduled back-up processes though, to ensure compliance with potential future requests for information in conjunction with legal proceedings and public safety.

Users wishing to remain a Meltdownchallenge.com participants, without any email or text notifications and/or communication from other participants can unsubscribe at unsubscribe@Meltdownchallenge.com. However, system emails (such as those regarding forgotten user passwords) and legal notices (such as updates to our policies) will still be sent.

Users can request access to Personal Information that Meltdownchallenge.com has stored but that is not available on User Profile pages, so they can correct inaccuracies and/or request deletion of information. Meltdownchallenge.com responds to such requests within 15 business days. Users can also request deletion of their entire account by contacting us. Meltdownchallenge.com responds to these requests within 20 business days.

###  Statistics, De-identified and Aggregated Information Usage

Meltdownchallenge.com may use statistics, de-identified aka anonymous and/ or aggregated information collected through Meltdownchallenge.com to improve our services, and for research and analyses, including but not limited to clinical medical research. We may also provide this information to our partners for similar purposes. De-identified information in this context does not consist of personally identifiable private records, such as name, email address, or address; but may include gender, height, weight, zip code, and medical information. Aggregated information in this context consists of grouped information from multiple users and is not associated with individual user accounts. If you are participating in Meltdownchallenge.com through a company, be aware that the use of your data, no matter on what basis, may be restricted or prohibited entirely, depending upon the agreement between Meltdownchallenge.com and your company.

###  Email and Mobile Alerts

Meltdownchallenge.com sends several email messages based upon personally identifiable information the users has provided. These messages include emails pertaining but not limited to welcoming users to the website, challenge reminders, account management, activity notifications, motivational tips, health tips etc. Email and texts may also be used to carry out reminder settings and ensure users are informed of the latest improvements or other challenges relating to Meltdownchallenge.com. Meltdownchallenge.com will send reminders and alerts throug e-mail and/or mobile phone. Users have control over the amount of these reminders and alerts, to the point of disabling them entirely.

For questions about this policy, contact legal@meltdownchallenge.com.

###  Cookies Usage

Meltdownchallenge.com uses session ID and persistent cookies to enable users to sign in and to personalize health challenges. Cookies are small text file stored on a user’s hard disk by a web server and/or browser. Session ID cookies expire as soon as the browser is closed while persistent cookies are stored on hard disks for longer periods of time. Cookies are assigned individually and uniquely to users, and only a web server within the domain that created/assigned the cookie can read your cookies. Cookies therefore can not be used for running harmful programs or adding viruses to computers.

The main purpose of cookies is providing convenience to users by saving time. Cookies for example remember settings for certain sites so users don’t have to adjust them separately. Using cookies simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and eases site navigation. When users return to the web site, they can retrieve the information they previously provided, so they can easily use the site's features that were customized.

Partners, vendors and affiliates of MeltdownChallenge.com also use cookies to identify user’s browsers and gain inisght into what pages of our website are visited and by how many people. This information is provided to MeltdownChallenge.com, but is not personally identifiable. However, some of our business partners, like advertisers, may also use cookies on MeltdownChallenge.com. We have no access to nor control over these cookies. Therefore the usage of cookies by third parties does not fall under this privacy policy.

Users have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but users can usually modify browser settings to decline some or all cookies. If users choose to decline all cookies, they may not be able to use interactive features of this or other web sites that depend on cookies.

###  Minors

Minors under 18 years of age are prohibited from registering on MeltdownChallenge.com. Users under this age should not attempt to register our site and/or send any information about themselves to us. However, legal guardians may sign up minors. MeltdownChallenge.com does not knowingly allow users under age 18 to register nor collect information about them. If MeltdownChallenge.com disovers it has registered minors and/or information about them, that information will be deleted immediately. MeltdownChallenge.com requests users to contact us if they suspect we have information from or about a minor under 18 years old.
